<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rcx | hacklog</title>
    <link>https://sjp38.github.io/tags/rcx/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://sjp38.github.io/tags/rcx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>rcx</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 09:05:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://sjp38.github.io/img/tux.png</url>
      <title>rcx</title>
      <link>https://sjp38.github.io/tags/rcx/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eurosys&#39;20 will be held online</title>
      <link>https://sjp38.github.io/post/eurosys20_will_be_held_online/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 09:05:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sjp38.github.io/post/eurosys20_will_be_held_online/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the upload of the accepted papers list, EuroSys homepage also updated its
notice about COVID-19 related notification.  It previously tried to reschedule
the offline meeting, however seems they changed mind and decided to do virtual
(online) conference.  It&amp;rsquo;s a bad news for authors and people who planned to
participate the offline meetings, but a good new for other people, because they
would be allowed to participate in the conference without fee.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RCX: Read-Copy Transact</title>
      <link>https://sjp38.github.io/post/rcx/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 09:11:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sjp38.github.io/post/rcx/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Read-copy update (RCU) can provide ideal scalability for read-mostly workloads,
but some believe that it provides only poor performance for updates. This
belief is due to the lack of RCU-centric update synchronization mechanisms. RCU
instead works with a range of update-side mechanisms, such as locking. In fact,
many developers embrace simplicity by using global locking. Logging, hardware
transactional memory, or fine-grained locking can provide better scalability,
but each of these approaches has limitations, such as imposing overhead on
readers or poor scalability on non-uniform memory access (NUMA) systems, mainly
due to their lack of NUMA-aware design principles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project introduces an RCU extension (RCX) that provides highly scalable
RCU updates on NUMA systems while retaining RCU’s read-side benefits. RCX
combines hardware transactional memory (HTM) and traditional locking based on
our NUMA-aware design principles for RCU. Micro-benchmarks on a NUMA system
having 144 hardware threads show RCX has up to 22.61 times better performance
and up to 145.00 times lower HTM abort rates compared to a state-of-the-art
RCU/HTM combination. To demonstrate the effectiveness and applicability of RCX,
we have applied RCX to parallelize some of the Linux kernel memory management
system and an in-memory database system. The optimized kernel and the database
show up to 24 and 17 times better performance compared to the original version,
respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;source-code&#34;&gt;Source Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The source code of RCX is available at: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rcx-sync&#34;&gt;https://github.com/rcx-sync&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications-and-presentations&#34;&gt;Publications and Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SeongJae Park, Paul E. McKenney, Laurent Dufour, Heon Y. Yeom, &lt;strong&gt;An HTM-Based
Update-side Synchronization for RCU on NUMA systems.&lt;/strong&gt; In &lt;em&gt;15th ACM European
Conference on Computer Systems (EuroSys)&lt;/em&gt;, April 2020.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3342195.3387527&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QydRe1z5uYk&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;Video (Short)&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=h7RzyhR_lPQ&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&#34;&gt;Video (Long)&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurosys2020.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/04/slides/166_seongjae_slides.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurosys2020.org/program/&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;news&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2020-04-19&lt;/em&gt;: The EuroSys&#39;20 paper is uploaded at
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3342195.3387527&#34;&gt;ACM DL&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2020-04-04&lt;/em&gt;: The accepted papers list of EuroSys&#39;20 has
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurosys2020.org/program/accepted-papers/&#34;&gt;uploaded&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2020-02-14&lt;/em&gt;: The paper introducing RCX has accepted to be presented by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eurosys2020.org/&#34;&gt;EuroSys&#39;20&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
