<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>About on hacklog</title>
    <link>https://sjp38.github.io/tags/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in About on hacklog</description>
    <image>
      <title>hacklog</title>
      <url>https://sjp38.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://sjp38.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.131.0</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://sjp38.github.io/tags/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://sjp38.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sjp38.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description> Recent &amp;amp; Upcoming Talks Ongoing &amp;amp; Past Projects Linux kernel contribution history (LWN subscription is required) As of 2025-11-01, made 996 commits for Linux kernel in total. Recent Publications CV </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://sjp38.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sjp38.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Active DAMON: Data Access Monitor damo hackermail Lazybox Inactive Translation of &amp;ldquo;Is Parallel Programming Hard, And, If So, What Can You Do About It?&amp;rdquo; stream-track RCX: Read-Copy Transact GCMA: Guaranteed Contiguous Memory Allocator DAPHICX: Data Access Pattern Hint Injecting Compiler Extension </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>https://sjp38.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sjp38.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>SeongJae Park, Page-level and Fleet-wide Data Access Monitoring for Meta. In Linux Plumbers Refereed Track, Dec 2025. Link SeongJae Park, Actionable Data Access Monitoring Output Data and Format. In Linux System Monitoring and Observability MC at Linux Plumbers, Dec 2025. Link SeongJae Park, DAMON-based Pages Migration for {C,G,X}PU [un]attached NUMA nodes. In Device and Specific PurposeMemory MC at Linux Plumbers, Dec 2025. Link SeongJae Park, hkml: Mailing Tool for Simple Linux Kernel Development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recent Publications</title>
      <link>https://sjp38.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://sjp38.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>SeongJae Park, Madhuparna Bhowmik, Alexandru Uta, DAOS: Data Access-aware Operating System. In The 31st International ACM Symposium on High-Performance Parallel and Distributed Computing (HPDC&#39;22), June 2022. Paper, Slides, Poster SeongJae Park, Paul E. McKenney, Laurent Dufour, Heon Y. Yeom, An HTM-Based Update-side Synchronization for RCU on NUMA systems. In 15th ACM European Conference on Computer Systems (EuroSys), April 2020. Paper, Video (5min, 12min), Slides SeongJae Park, Yunjae Lee, Heon Y.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
