<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>damon | hacklog</title>
    <link>/ko/tags/damon/</link>
      <atom:link href="/ko/tags/damon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>damon</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>ko-kr</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 18:21:07 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/tux.png</url>
      <title>damon</title>
      <link>/ko/tags/damon/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAMON: Data Access Monitor</title>
      <link>/ko/post/damon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2019 18:21:07 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/ko/post/damon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modern workloads tend to have huge working sets and low locality.  Despite this
trend, the capacity of DRAM has not been increased enough to accommodate such
huge working sets. Therefore, memory management mechanisms optimized for such
modern workloads are widely required today. For such optimizations, knowing the
data access pattern of given workloads is essential. However, manually
extracting such patterns from huge and complex workloads is exhaustive. Worse
yet, existing memory access analysis tools incur unacceptably high overheads
for unnecessarily detailed analysis results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mitigate this situation, we introduce a tool that is designed for data
access pattern tracing. Two core mechanisms in this tool, a region-based
sampling and an adaptive region adjustment, allow users to limit the tracing
overhead in a bounded range regardless of the size and complexity of target
workloads, while preserving the quality of results. Our empirical evaluations
that conducted with 20 realistic workloads show the high quality, low overhead,
and a potential use case of this tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;news&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2020-02-20&lt;/em&gt;: The second RFC of Data Access Monitoring-based Operating Schems
(DAMOS) has introduced by LWN&#39;s
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lwn.net/Articles/812408/&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Kernel patches of interest&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2020-02-10&lt;/em&gt;: The first RFC of Data Access Monitoring-based Operating Schemes
(DAMOS) has posted to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lore.kernel.org/linux-mm/20200210150921.32482-1-sjpark@amazon.com/&#34;&gt;LKML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2020-01-23&lt;/em&gt;: The RFC of DAMON has introduced by LWN&#39;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://lwn.net/Articles/809100/&#34;&gt;&amp;lsquo;Kernel patches of
interest&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2020-01-20&lt;/em&gt;: The first RFC patchset of DAMON has posted to
&lt;a href=&#34;https://lore.kernel.org/linux-mm/20200110131522.29964-1-sjpark@amazon.com/&#34;&gt;LKML&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publications-and-presentations&#34;&gt;Publications and Presentations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SeongJae Park, Yunjae Lee, Heon Y. Yeom, &lt;strong&gt;Profiling Dynamic Data Access
Patterns with Controlled Overhead and Quality.&lt;/strong&gt; In 20th ACM/IFIP
International Middleware Conference Industry, December 2019.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3368125&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SeongJae Park, &lt;strong&gt;Tracing Data Access Pattern with Bounded Overhead and
Best-effort Accuracy.&lt;/strong&gt; In &lt;em&gt;The Linux Kernel Summit&lt;/em&gt;, September 2019.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxplumbersconf.org/event/4/contributions/548/attachments/311/590/damon_ksummit19.pdf&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href=&#34;https://linuxplumbersconf.org/event/4/contributions/548/&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SeongJae Park, Yunjae Lee, Yunhee Kim, Heon Y. Yeom, &lt;strong&gt;Profiling Dynamic Data
Access Patterns with Bounded Overhead and Accuracy.&lt;/strong&gt; In IEEE International
Workshop on Foundations and Applications of Self-* Systems (FAS* 2019),
June 2019.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/8791992&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
